Lucius P. Deming Papers
Lucius P. Deming Papers
1807-1919
Deming, Lucius P.
3 linear ft.
Papers of the manufacturer of women's clothing in New Haven, Connecticut. Collection includes scrapbooks, 1807-1919, containing periodical articles and newspaper clippings relating to Deming and a variety of subjects he found interesting. Also, a number of single issues of popular periodicals, mostly 1867.
148938
Biographical History
The collection suggests that Lucius P. Deming was an American manufacturer of women's clothing in New Haven, Connecticut. The collection also suggests he was a lawyer and judge. The two may have been the same Deming or a father and son.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Lucius P. Deming Papers comprise published material and scrapbooks.
Published material consists mainly of magazines of the late 1800's, including Godey's Lady's Book, Peterson's Magazine, Harper's New Monthly Magazine, and Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly. The 19 volumes of Scrapbooks contain primarily clippings, but also a few letters, handwritten items, ledger pages, sketches, notes, and other miscellanea.
Arrangement of the Collection
Materials are divided as described above; within that, items are in no particular order.
Subject and Genre Headings
Politics, government and public administration; Deming, Lucius P.; Fashion -- 19th century -- United States.; Fashion -- History.; New Haven (Conn.) -- History.; Scrapbooks.; Periodicals.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Published material
  - Magazine fragments
    - Miscellaneous, 1861; 1867,; undated (Box 1)
      Godey's Lady's Book and Magazine, December, 1861 (fashion, historical, and literary articles)
      Unidentified fragments
      Peterson's Magazine, April, 1867
      Peterson's Ladies National Magazine, April, 1867
      Peterson's Magazine, October, 1867
    - Peterson's Magazine, June, 1867; November, 1867;; December, 1867 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1867; 1869,; undated (Box 1)
      The Atlantic Almanac for 1869
      Peterson's Magazine, May, 1867
      Harper's New Monthly Magazine, undated
    - Miscellaneous, 1867; undated (Box 1)
      Peterson's Magazine, March, 1867
      Unidentified
      Peterson's Magazine, August, 1867
    - Peterson's Magazine, January, 1867 (Box 1)
    - The Dollar Monthly Magazine, January to July, 1863 (Box 1)
    - The Atlantic Almanac, 1869 (Box 1)
    - Our Boys and Girls, November 12, 1870 (Box 1)
    - Demorest's Young America, July, 1869 (Box 1)
    - Godey's Lady's Book and Magazine, March, 1859 (Box 1)
    - The Lady's Friend, March, 1868 (Box 1)
    - American Agriculturist, June, 1866; July, 1866 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1871; undated (Box 1)
      Frank Leslie's Popular Monthly
      Harper's Weekly, December 9, 1871
  - Newspaper clipping fragments, 1892-1894 (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks
  - Volume 1, 1807-1911 (Box 3)
    Note: this book was an actual ledger for a business-the clippings have been pasted in over many of the entries.
    Albany Sales Book written on front flyleaf 1807-1850; illustration plates (Civil War) 1861-1865; Los Angeles Times Illustrated Weekly Magazine, 1911; poetry clippings, etchings, lithograph; ledger entries showing shipment by water; handwritten poetry; pieces of what seems to be greeting cards or fashion plates
  - Volume 2, 1880-1912 (Box 1)
    Includes "Biennial Report of the Commissioners to Manage Yosemite Valley and the Mariposa Big Tree Grove 1891-92"; articles on Irish Relief Committee, also clippings containing printed letters from different Irish counties that give accounts of the famine in the 1870's-80's; clippings on issue of Home Rule for Ireland.
  - Volume 3, 1876-1880 (Box 1)
    Assorted clippings; p4 mentions L.P. Deming & Cooke as a cloak manufactuer and as adding a lingerie department; p52-53 has inserted sheets of paper listing "Hon. Lucius P. Deming, Judge' as part of the masthead of the City Court of New Haven (Connecticut); p57 has clipping of death notice for "Laura E., wife of Lucius P. Deming"
  - Volume 4, 1869-1872 (Box 3)
    Note: this book was an actual ledger for a business-the clippings have been pasted in over many of the entries; some of the accounts in the ledger include the Oneida Community, The Elm City Co., Calhoun, Robbins & Co., and Wallingford Community.
    Front page contains label of "Lucius P. Deming successor to C.B. Burwell retail dealer in Ladies' Dress Trimmings", etc.; some rough sketches of coats of arms; a handwritten piece of prose about history; an Index on p391; handwritten line on last page "Nothing is from all parts happy."
  - Volume 5, 1892-1919 (Box 1)
    Assorted clippings (political, economic, etc.); p16-17 slip of paper with Deming-Clarke Mica Mining Company general office Auburn, NY; mine office Ingalls, NC; LP Deming, Sec'y and Gen'l Mgr.; p48-49 Christmas Card (1915) from a William S. Hutchinson to Lucius P. Deming, P.G.M., Grand Lodge I.O.O.F. of Connecticut, 49 Aurelius Ave., Auburn, New York
  - Volume 6, 1878-1880 (Box 1)
    Clippings: crime and its punishment (ie. prison conditions)
  - Volume 7, 1884-1915 (Box 1)
    Clippings: speeches of a Henry W. Grady of The Atlanta Constitution (about some issue of the day); p62 clippings speaking of Judge L.P. Deming; history clippings
  - Volume 8, 1869-1897 (Box 3)
    Includes clippings from The Syracuse Daily Journal (newpaper), many of which are of a column by Bill Nye, who is traveling worldwide and giving accounts of these travels; copy of The Manufacturer and Builder, Vol. 1, 1869 nos. 1-12 (Jan.-Dec.); Practical Journal of Industrial Progress 380 p.
  - Volume 9, 1884-1919 (Box 1)
    Clippings on the Conant-McClellan murder case in New London, Conn.; several parts of The Syracuse Herald (1915, 1918), one piece of The Post-Standard (1919)
  - Volume 10, 1877-1883 (Box 1)
    Clippings are mainly human interest; p92-93 piece of paper stating "State Prison Contract Labor Commission" listing Lucius P. Deming as a commissioner; p96 in an article about the Fair Haven Cemetery, Lucius P. Deming is listed as a director for the year 1882; some clippings p. 100-101 are old time 'cures' and recipes for liniment, etc.
  - Volume 11, 1881-1891 (Box 2)
    Includes political tickets and a sheet of paper with "Scrap bks from Dr. W. Freeman Galpin not wanted for Vc or a Vc" written on it; clippings (political and economic); p81 has a canvass ticket for New Haven, Ct. for the candidate Lynde Harrison (Oct. 18, 1884) signed byLucius P. Deming as the 'Chairman Town Committee'; p86 & 87 have the printed 'Rules of the Republican Party in the Town of New Haven'
  - Volume 12, 1876-1890 (Box 2)
    Letter about the raising of funds for the pedestal of the Staute of Liberty; clippings about the "Sons of Revolutionary Sires"; also notices of deaths of the members of the above organization; also materials about the "Society of Sons of the American Revolution" (had state-designated chapters); p45 form letter listing Lucius P. Deming as President of the New Haven, Conn. chapter of The Connecticut Society of the Sons of the Revolution; p102-103 copies of both House and Senate bills to incorporate the Sons of the American Revolution (Deming was listed as one of the incorporators)
  - Volume 13, 1882 (Box 2)
    Inside front cover is handwritten notes of Yale Law School Lectures in International Law, President Woolsey; clippings are mainly law (includes Malley case)
  - Volume 14 (continuation of Volume 13), 1882-1914 (Box 2)
    Malley case clippings; clippings of HM Brooks case
  - Volume 15, 1880-1883 (Box 2)
    Assorted clippings (political, economic, general, crime); p46-53 party election tickets; p96 has listing of Judge Deming's City Court cases
  - Volume 16, 1879-1884 (Box 2)
    Assorted clippings (law), including Holmes's trial; prison conditions
  - Volume 17, 1875-1895 (Box 2)
    Assorted clippings (human interest, etc.); p14-15 has clippings of published letters which have the initials LPD written in on top of them and signed by D., the subject of the letters is a vacation taken by the writer in the Adirondacks; p79 article clipped from May 22, 1884 speaks of Dr. L.P. Deming; p83 clipping of Judge Deming
  - Volume 18, 1879-1881 (Box 2)
    Clippings (political, general interest, prison system)
  - Volume 19, 1864-1881 (Box 3)
    Clippings (general interest, politics, economics); p41-49 have clippings of Bourbon Ballads (folk tunes); p120-121 containes a signed, handwritten letter, apparently written to Deming, but with fairly illegible handwriting
- Published material
  - Magazine fragments, 1866 (Box 3)